Szymon Pulut

szymon.pulut@gmail.com | (+48) 509 501 792

linkedin.com/in/szymonpulut szymonpulut.com github.com/szymonpulut

I am a web developer focused mostly on frontend, with working experience in basic devops, and basic experience in backend development. I am used to fast paced development using bleeding edge technologies, but I do not steer away from code ownership and maintenance. As a part of my hobbyist coding, I also touched on mobile app development in React Native (with Expo), Swift & Java, Arduino programming, and many more.

Work experience

June 2020 - now: Web Developer - Tango Digital Agency - Cracow, Poland:

I work in small teams or solo, creating web applications or their MVPs in newest technologies (TypeScript, React stack). After initially working only with frontend I branched out to also do devops – I perform basic operations (Docker & Terraform configuration, integration with cloud services, CI/CD setup). Due to the nature of projects, my insight and contributions (not just code) have been critical to success numerous times.

Projects I worked on:

- **GetBeans.com** digital B2B marketplace for coffee industry. My responsibility was mostly developing existing app. Notably I developed Stripe payment integration and lots of UI features.
- **GetFix** digital marketplace for maintenance services. My responsibility was to deliver an MVP to earn next funding rounds. Notably I developed release environment using Docker, Terraform, AWS and CircleCI; I also created basic frontend framework.
- Roam Ascend an MVP application for a project in medical industry (smart knee orthosis). My responsibility was to create a supplement web app to mobile apps. Notably I developed release environment using similar technologies to GetFix and created frontend framework.

Relevant experience

July 2018 - September 2018 - February 2019:

"tANS compression on FPGA devices" - Internship, Jagiellonian University - Cracow, PL

- collaborated in a 2-person group and created a compression device on an FPGA internship
- received 3rd place award for the best project at FPGA Symposium in Krakow poster session & live demonstration (September)
- adapted project for use with J-PET (Jagiellonian Positron Emission Tomography) real time compression (September February)

Own project - Tablet Dashboard (a demo available on my portfolio site szymonpulut.com).

- · created a web application to display and interact with my custom smart home system
- integrated with: external weather, air quality and covid-19 data APIs, Google Calendar API, MQTT broker (enables control of other "smart" devices)

Education

October 2020 - now: Jagiellonian University - Cracow, Poland

Computer Science - Bachelor Studies (resumed studies, dropped due to personal situation)

- *courses* object-oriented programming, data structures & algorithms, web app development, computer networks, computer architecture, digital electronics, operating systems
- · online courses database architecture & design, basic algorithms, web app development
- currently reading Design Patterns E. Gamma, J. Vlissides, R. Helm, R. Johnson

I'm familiar with: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Query, Redux (thunk & basic saga), io-ts; Gatsby, GraphQL; Ant Design, Material-UI, styled-components; HTML5, CSS3; Docker, Terraform, CircleCI, AWS. I am proficient in using Unix based systems. I am bilingual – English & Polish.

I'm familiar with on a basic level: React Native with Expo; SASS, LESS; Webpack, Babel; Node, Express, MongoDB & PHP, MySQL; Java, C++. In the past I have worked with CraftCMS, Wordpress, Drupal.